Rong Zheng

(+1) 954-600-0861 | rzheng@fau.edu | U.S Citizen | https://zhengrongaift.github.io

CAREER PROFILE

Junior Software Developer with 2 years of experience in Embedded Software Development. Experienced in both manual and automated software and hardware testing methodologies.

Core competencies include Software Development, Software Architectures, Integration Test, Unit Test, Linux platform, Data Decryption, Network Protocols, Hardware Debug, and Firmware Testing.

EXPERIENCE

Lockheed Martin Orlando, FL

Software Engineer Associate (Missile and Fire Control)

Tools: C++, C, QT Creator, GIT, Agile, JIRA, Linux, Window

June 2020 — Present

Ford Motor Company

Sunrise, FL Jan 2020 — May 2020

Manufacturing Software Developer Co-op (SYNC Infotainment System)

- Technical debugging, troubleshooting, and log analysis to determine causes for software failures during manufacturing runs using C++ on Linux, batch script on Windows, and bash shell script on device builds.
- Provided general status and information about software sanity test results to the Software Development Manager and Product Development Team.
- Tools: C++, GIT, Agile, SonarQube, I2C, UART, SPI, QNX, JIRA, Jenkins, RTOS, Shell Script

Randstad Technologies US

Fort Lauderdale. FL

Embedded Software Engineer Intern (Caterpillar)

May 2019 — Jan 2020

- Provided unit tests for AIS (Autonomous Infrastructure Software) and CPM (Caterpillar Production Measurement). Debugged the application software using Object Oriented programming in C++.
- Developed new features based on user stories and loaded onto an ECM (Engine Control Module) for integration testing by using SSH.
- Tool: C++, GIT, Agile, SSH, Unix/Linux, Eclipse, Engine Control Module (ECM/ECU), CAN Bus

Hispanic Serving Institute

Davie, FL

Student Mentor

Jan 2019 — May 2020

- Conducted one-on-one tutoring sessions for college students in Algebra, Pre-Calculus, Calculus I, Calculus II, Java, C++, and Intro to C.
- Tools: C++, C, Java, Python, JavaScript, Code Debugging

EDUCATION

Florida Atlantic University

Bachelors in Computer Engineering, Bachelors in Computer Science

Graduated May 2020

• GPA: 3.77 / 4.00, Magna Cum Laude

PROJECTS

Automated Rescue Transportation Unit

Jan 2019 — Dec 2019

- Designed a dual control system for an on the water rescue unit by using Radio Control and WIFI network communication with Arduino Nano and Raspberry Pi.
- Implemented a user interface by using Node.JS for serial port communication for motor control.
- Tools: C, Node.JS, Python, Multimeter, Nginx, GIT, HTML, JavaScript, CSS, Bootstrap

MiniRHex Sep 2019 — Dec 2020

- Created a low cost, miniature scale hexapod robot by using an Arduino Nano microcontroller.
- Designed a software to control robotic legs remotely via Web user interface by using Raspberry Pi.
- Tools: C, Node.JS, Bluetooth, UART, GIT, HTML, JavaScript, CSS, Bootstrap